medylife.com 2016-04-25

# Privacy Policy | MedyLife

[ ](https://www.medylife.com/delhi) __

****This document contains important information that you need to consider before making an important decision.****

**1\. Introduction**

Medylife is committed to respecting the privacy rights of our customers, visitors, and other users of Medylife.com (the “Site”) and services provided by MedyLife through the Site (collectively, the “Services”). We created this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) to give you confidence as you visit and use the Services, and to demonstrate our commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy. This Privacy Policy is only applicable to our Site and information obtained by us from any of our marketing affiliates, and not to any other websites that you may be able to access from the Site or any website of Medylife’s business partners, each of which may have data collection, storage, and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Services is governed by this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use.  
BY USING THE SITE, SERVICES, AND/OR BY REGISTERING WITH US, YOU ACCEPT THE PRACTICES AND POLICIES OUTLINED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, AND YOU HEREBY CONSENT THAT WE WILL TRACK, COLLECT, USE, AND SHARE YOUR INFORMATION IN THE FOLLOWING WAYS. IF YOU ARE REGISTERING AN ACCOUNT OR USING THE SERVICES ON BEHALF OF AN INDIVIDUAL OR ENTITY OTHER THAN YOURSELF, YOU REPRESENT THAT YOU ARE AUTHORIZED BY SUCH INDIVIDUAL OR ENTITY TO ACCEPT THIS PRIVACY POLICY ON SUCH INDIVIDUAL’S OR ENTITY’S BEHALF.

**2\. Traffic Data Collected**

We automatically track and collect the following categories of information when you visit our Site: (1) IP addresses; (2) domain servers; (3) types of computers accessing the Site; (4) types of web browsers used to access the Site; (5) referring source which may have sent you to the Site; and (6) other information associated with the interaction of your browser and the Site (collectively “Traffic Data”).

**3\. Personal Information Collected**

In order for you to access certain areas of the Site or certain Services where it is important for us to know who you are so that we can best meet your needs, we may require you to provide us with certain information that personally identifies you (“Personal Information”). Personal Information includes the following categories of information: (1) contact data (such as your e-mail address, phone number and Medylife password); and (2) demographic data (such as your gender, your date of birth and your pin code); If you communicate with us by, for example, e-mail or letter, any information provided in such communication may be collected as Personal Information.

**4\. Interactive and Installed Tools**

We also collect other information, some of which may be Personal Information that you voluntarily provide to us when you choose to use some of the Services’ interactive tools and services (“Interactive Tools”), such as searching for Providers, searching for available appointments with Providers. We also collect information you provide voluntarily in free-form text boxes on the Site and through responses to surveys, questionnaires and the like.

**5\. Cookies**

We may use small computer files that are transferred to your computer’s hard drive that contain information such as user ID, user preferences, lists of pages visited and activities conducted while browsing the Site (“Cookies”) to help us improve our Site by tracking your navigation habits and to store some of your preferences. Generally, we use Cookies to customize your experience on our Site and to store your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Site. Cookies do not allow our site to gain access to other information on your computer. At your option, expense and responsibility, you may block Cookies or delete Cookies from your hard drive. However, by disabling Cookies, you may not have access to the entire set of features of the Site.

**6\. Website Analytics**

We may use third party website analytics services in connection with the Services, for example, to record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity, as well as any text that you type into the Site. These website analytics services do not collect Personal Information that you do not voluntarily enter into the Site. These services do not track your browsing habits across websites which do not use their services. We use the information collected from these services to find usability problems to make the Services easier to use. The recordings will never identify you or your account; they only record anonymous user information.

**7\. MedyLife’s Use of Your Information**

We may use your Personal Information to recommend certain resources or Providers. We may use your contact data to send you information about Medylife or our products or Services, to contact you when necessary, and in conjunction with your use of certain Interactive Tools. We may use your demographic data, Traffic Data to customize and tailor your experience through the Services, in emails and in other communications, displaying content that we think you might be interested in and according to your preferences. Use of the Services may require Medylife to use your Personal Information to allow your Providers to refer you to, and make appointments with, other Providers on your behalf. We may also use your anonymized Personal Information to run (or authorize third parties to run) statistical research on individual or aggregate health or medical trends. Such research would only use your Personal Information in an anonymous manner that cannot be tied directly back to you.

**8\. Sharing of Information**

We share certain categories of information we collect from you in the ways described in this Privacy Policy, including as described below:

  * You may choose to authorize Medylife to share your Personal Information with selected Providers.
  * We may share your contact data, Traffic Data, demographic data with Providers you choose to schedule through the Services.
  * In order to customize your advertising interactions, we may share Personal Information with marketing affiliates and other third parties only on an aggregate (i.e., anonymized) basis.
  * We may share your anonymized Personal Information with third parties to enable them to run statistical research on individual or aggregate health or medical trends.
  * We share Personal Information and Traffic Data with our business partners who assist us by performing core services (such as hosting or data storage and security) related to our operation of the Services and/or by making certain Interactive Tools available to our users. Those business partners have their own Privacy Policy and Medylife does not exercise control over them. You are requested to have a look at their privacy policy. However they will only use your contact data and other Personal Information to carry out their specific business obligations to Medylife and to provide your requested medical care and services.
  * We may share your contact data with our subcontractors to enable them to send you Medylife promotional materials. These subcontractors will only use your contact data to send you Medylife promotional materials.
  * We may share certain marketing metrics including, but not limited to, anonymized Personal Information and non-personal Information, with our business partners to help determine the effectiveness of certain advertising campaigns.
  * We may transfer information about you to another company in connection with a merger, sale or acquisition by or of Medylife. In this event, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. Medylife does not share, sell, rent or trade your Personal Information with any third parties for their promotional purposes.

**9\. User Choice**

You may choose not to provide us with any Personal Information. In such an event, you can still access and use some of the Services; however you will not be able to access and use certain key features of the Services that require your Personal Information.

**10\. Confidentiality and Security**

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will keep your Personal Information private and will not share it with third parties, unless we believe in good faith that disclosure of your Personal Information or any other information we collect about you is necessary to: (1) comply with a court order or other legal process; (2) protect the rights, property or safety of Medylife or another party; (3) enforce our Terms of Use; or (4) respond to claims that any posting or other content violates the rights of third-parties.

**11\. Health Care Providers**

Health Care Providers, their employees, and their agents should be particularly aware of their obligations of patient confidentiality both in communicating with MedyLife and in responding to a review of their services posted on our Site. MedyLife does not have, and will not accept, any obligations of confidentiality with respect to any communications other than those expressly stated in this Privacy Policy and MedyLife’s Terms of Use.

**12\. Public Information**

Any information that you may reveal in a review posting or other online discussion or forum is intentionally open to the public and is not in any way private. You should think carefully before disclosing any personally identifiable information in any public forum. What you have written may be seen and/or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict.

**13\. Security**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. For example, when you enter sensitive information on our Site, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (“SSL”).  
Although we make good faith efforts to store Personal Information in a secure operating environment that is not open to the public, you should understand that there is no such thing as complete security, and we do not guarantee that there will be no unintended disclosures of your Personal Information. If we become aware that your Personal Information has been disclosed in a manner not in accordance with this Privacy Policy, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you of the nature and extent of the disclosure (to the extent we know that information) as soon as reasonably possible and as permitted by law.

**14\. Lost or Stolen Information**

You must promptly notify us if your contact data is lost, stolen, or used without permission. In such an event, we will remove that contact data from your account and update our records accordingly.

**15\. Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this Privacy Policy so please review it frequently. If we do, then we will post the amended Privacy Policy on the Site; we may also attempt to notify you in some other way. In all cases, use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.

**16\. Controlling Your Personal Information**

As a registered user of the Services, you can modify some of the Personal Information you have included in your profile or change your username by logging in and accessing your account. Upon your request, Medylife will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete your account and the Personal Information in your profile; however, it may be impossible to remove your account without some residual information being retained by Medylife.

**17\. Links to Other Websites**

The Site contains links to third party websites to which Medylife has no affiliation. Medylife does not share your Personal Information with those websites and is not responsible for their privacy practices. Some websites may have the look and feel of our Site. Please be aware that you may be on a different site and that this Privacy Policy only covers our Site. A link to a website does not constitute or imply endorsement by Medylife.

**18\. Contacts**

If you have any comments, concerns or questions about this Privacy Policy, please drop an email to – [help@medylife.com](mailto:help@medylife.com) or contact us at:  
Medy Info Solutions  
G-11 Aditya Plaza-2  
Kaushambi, Ghaziabad-201010  
UP, India  
0120-4318090
